Sara Bagheri

https://sarabagherii.github.io/

sara@empowerbi.com

Bucharest, Romania

Skills

I am a data analyst with a statistical background, passionate about uncovering hidden stories within datasets. I have consulting experience working with students and researchers. I enjoy collaborating with teams to achieve goals and sharing knowledge.

Experience

Empower BI / Business Analyst/Data Scientist

November 2022 - Present, Bucharest, Romania.

Participated in a project for Lagardere Travel Retail where we had to build a sales forecast for all their 300 + Stores which would later be used in the Replenishment Process. We created a MicroStrategy transactional/analytical application which is used by the Store managers for all items replenishment/reorder on a weekly basis. To create the sales forecast, we first had then flatten the data then used multiple regression and time series for forecasting. My role here was doing the business analysis as well as creating the forecasting models. I also started the MicroStrategy Departmental Analyst and Enterprise Analyst courses and planning to take the certification in the coming weeks.

AUSTROGLASS SRL / Process Control Specialist

November 2021 – July 2022, Bucharest, Romania.

Monitored operational processes and reported on them daily. Constructed pivot tables and charts using Microsoft Excel, and created dashboards using Power BI. Trained my colleagues to use Power BI.

Ofoq Kourosh / Business Analyst/Data Analyst

February 2019 – June 2021, Tehran, Iran.

Worked in the company's analytics department creating a BI solution for sales, inventory, accounts payable/receivable and purchasing analysis. Acted as a liaison between business and IT. Conducted interviews with business then transformed the requirements into specifications for the Data Warehouse Architects and Power BI developers. Also, because of my Statistical and Mathematical knowledge I was involved in creating the algorithm for our customers clustering project based on their purchasing history and demographic profile.

Freelancer / Statistical Analysis Consultant

August 2018 – December 2018, Tehran, Iran.

provided guidance and support to researchers who needed assistance with statistical analysis.

Sorosh Saramadan Institute/ Statistical Analysis Consultant

January 2015 – June 2018, Kermanshah, Iran.

Consulted master students and researchers in statistical analysis. Helped them to collect and analyze data, and improved their software knowledge, including SPSS, AMOS, Eviews and SmartPLS.

Niloo Sales agency / Assistant accountant, part-time

December 2014 – November 2015, Kermanshah, Iran.

Processed accounts payable and receivable, prepared financial reports, performed administrative tasks such as filing and answering emails and phone calls.

Islamic Azad University/ Adjunct Lecturer

August 2012 – February 2013, Kermanshah, Iran.

Taught statistics for management and the utilization of SPSS in research.

Education

Google / Data Analytics Professional Certificate

September 2022- January 2023, Online

$\frac{https://www.coursera.org/account/accomplishments/specialization/certificat}{e/ZQN4S6MZRAJ9}$

Completed eight courses, that included hands-on, practice-based assessments and analytical skills (data cleaning, analysis, & visualization) and tools (spreadsheets, SQL, R programming, Tableau)

Statistical Software in Social Sciences / Project-Based Course

December 2014 - March 2015, Razi University

learned data analysis using SPSS and presented the results in a standard format.

Mathematical Statistics / Master

September 2012-October 2014, Razi University

Thesis title: Optimal Designs for some special cases of Generalized Linear Models with Group Effects.

Statistics / Bachelor

September 2008-July 2012, Razi University

Awards

Was selected as one of the top students in the Bachelor's and Master's programs in the field of Statistics.